okay guys Luke Stratton here first
lighting director commentary video
having watched this video and every year
but man let's see how I did I'm excited
to watch so I was gonna start with the
red and then I'm cutting there the
yellow low beams which is the slow fade
up to a position called halo it's a
prism effect slow fade down
[Applause]
my finger there I'm just getting ready
for a prism speed that's prison speed
and a gobo scroll boom back to open
another slow position fade
I might wipe in blue here yeah wipe in
cyan wipe in blue and those are my
specials or leak o's just some guys
would call them and i black the rest of
the rig out now you know on this rig
those are LED fixtures that it's just a
white color takeover but on a bigger rig
I might actually have leak O's there you
can see on my left hand I'm getting the
look ready there I'm here I'm fading in
some led wash time some problems there
clearly with the specials and back to
the before rig here
I've made out the specials with my left
hand
[Music]
oh yeah those are the moles the house
blinders was a cyan wipe and then took
out the spots and beams back to the
specials her up like that just waiting
for my next cue here thinking about
what's gonna happen that's a position
fade there in the middle slow on my
right hand there I'm controlling
position fade speed all my position cues
are linked to the same rate fader
now you can see it's live so you know
sometimes I'm a little late but it
happens man
a little gobo actually here with the
five faceted flat prism on the points
and the moles back to the full rig
[Music]
back to the position down and go moles
again
and that's a color effect that's an all
white strobe there on my right hand and
I'm all that nonsense up top is just
teaching positions
[Music]
orange-yellow way
no one knows but that's probably not
what I normally do so there of my right
hand I triggered an ocean waves movement
effect which is just like a stage wash
kind of moves around on the stage and
brought everything back back down to
nice dark blue
then you can see what while we're kind
of hanging out here every time I click a
look but you can see there's three
colors in the middle of my screen those
three colors get updated some guys call
them ghost colors I just call them
effects colors but then I have a whole
page of things that are written with
those three colors so if I fire a new
look like those those three palettes get
rewritten and I can do all kinds of
effects inside those three colors here
we're just kind of moving around
lighting up the sake of it this position
is called down X fan
and some strobes here you can't see in
my right hand there I'm doing just some
color bumps on which we what would be
the ex keys on a full-size ma
probably high-speed gobo scroll here
yeah which I already had queued up it
just was blocked out so it's just white
with everything in a I speak of a scroll
fitting in position here my right hand
is getting the prison rotation speed
slowing it down and then I'm adding
color rotate our color scroll rainbow
effect there's some probably some chases
some shutter chases right here
stick it too good to get yep and those
are just on a fader for their speed
button with the right-hand fader for the
speed
[Applause]
yeah there they are again the shutter
chases and those are like on the right
hand there those are just blackout
lights to blackout with an immediate
release following it and here I got a
lock so I can lock the wash to that
scrim which is like the double pod logo
probably see it more right here
[Music]
there it is scrim so that way I can go
to any other position with the rig and
those will stay there
some guys split up how they move the rig
but I make everything move together
because that's how I think about
compositionally but sometimes I one
thing to say in the same spot
[Music]
[Applause]
coming up here I'm Rob ibly gonna start
grabbing hits with the kick drum but you
know sometimes you got to pick a rhythm
there's lots of rhythms and this time I
picked the kick drum then going back to
the full rig here a little late but it
happens
and this here is a color stack you're
gonna see boom boom it's just called
scary monster and horror flick when I
click it once it's UV red and next is
red Eevee this one's called electric
forest and that's just the color is not
the position and back to kick drum hits
here little late
[Music]
that's a dimmer effect just left to
right on a fader you know you can see
I'm getting my prison rotation time
ready and here go big and that's just a
bouncing shutter effect the whole rig
I'm probably gonna get white strobes
here did you do that yeah and that's one
button that just stroeve's the whole
rigging wait so I can just leave it in
red and add that in whenever I want it
and now here comes the big yeah big
symmetrical circle effect one thing I
love about that symmetrical circle
effect is that it keys off of four
different room presets and up down and
in and out
so each day I can make sure it doesn't
hit the walls and it stays with within
the audience's eye vision area
[Music]
yeah there was a bug in there where I
turn off sometimes when I turn off that
scrim lock it it was resetting my
effects but I think I fixed it so you
can see I'm a little away what's going
on I I gotta figure it out that it
happens man you gotta roll with the
punches
shudder chase Stroeve Dennis
yeah so just you know white and red I'm
hitting strobes that's the malls the
button there a third button on the right
a PCS when I hold it it goes like a
frost on everything and CTO used to be
white but uh Nick kabila one of my texts
was like hey man why don't you make that
one's like warmer so to this day it
stays warm and I like it a lot sometimes
on the festival regard the moles into
that queue too but not always this color
scroll nice big fade up probably some
solid colors in and out Wow yeah there
we go
yeah man big shout out to em k Devo for
making that happen if you guys liked
what you saw check out the podcast it's
called the light side it's on iTunes and
SoundCloud I'm Luke thanks for watching